Dr. Julie, we need to have a word.
I'm on your profile now, and there's
something I need to say. Your content
is fantastic.
It is elite, gold tier,
and I send so many people
to come look at your page
that I felt like it was only fair
that I make a
video about this. First of all,
you're a fox.
I know you're a taken woman.
I know we're due to do a podcast in the
new year, but
I'm getting it off my chest.
I think you're a bit of a cougar,
and I'm sure
millions of other men do as well,
in a professional sense.
It wouldn't be fair for me to carry on
doing this video without making that
abundantly clear. Now,
what I want to do is use your
content to point out to people just how
immaculately
good you are at what you do.
And your book is good.
Well done for that.
So let's look at your most recent post.
mistake when you're working on your own
happiness.
Don't make this mistake
when you're working on your own happiness.
Hook.
Because people think straight away, "Well,
what mistakes I might make wanting my
own happiness?" And also,
everyone's striving for happiness.
So when we think about the target size of
the amount of people this could be
perfect for, it's like nine billion. Cool.
Imagine this is you.
The setup, straight into it.
Again,
we're building curiosity here by saying,
"How can I relate to a goldfish?"
And this is your life.
Now you're calling my life a water tank
where a fish lives?
Like most people's lives, there
are problems that can make it toxic.
Suddenly we've got a dash of relatability.
Other people have toxic lives
and issues that are happening?
Fish is living in a toxic environment.
Eventually, it gets sick,
so you take her out of the
dirty water and put her in a new tank for
a while.
Fantastic transition. By the way guys,
think for a second.
When we're talking about raising the
stakes, Dr.
Julie here has had to pollute a tank,
go away, empty it, fill it up, clean,
probably wipe it out a bit,
fill it with water, bring it back,
move over to the
side, bring it back in,
start the edit for that transition.
The effort that she would've had to have
put in here for this, unless she had two
tanks. Well,
she had to buy a tank in the first place.
I very much doubt
that she's got a fish sitting in a plastic
bag on the kitchen
side so she can make this video.
She's probably got a house full of props,
if
that's not a studio. Anyway.
Kind of like how you take a break,
you go on holiday for a few weeks into a
new
environment, and it-
I'm listening.
I've got the emotive response from the
audio, but then at the
same time,
I've got something to look at with my
eyes.
It's like a perfect trifecta of attention
... helps. Everything gets better
and feels great for a while,
until you return and go right back to
that toxic
situation again.
And it doesn't matter how clean the water
was on your break
or how refreshed you feel. Eventually,
you will get sick again.
If you want to thrive in the long term,
you have to focus on cleaning up the
environment that is affecting you every
day.
I'm a psychologist. Follow for more.
417,000 likes.
Hundreds of thousands of people
influenced for the better.
It's incredible.
But there is something you all
are missing, and before we get to this,
I must say, Dr. Julie,
I am going to apologize for what I'm about
to do.
Here's your first post. What's that?
Nearly 10 years ago.
I'm not even sure if that's you.
And for a very long time, you just posted
photos,
and I assume this would've been because
you probably were too
scared to be on camera. And this
is kind of the beautiful thing
that I want to show
everyone watching this as a content
creator. The GOAT, Dr.
Julie,
started in the exact same place you are.
2019,
this is still the peak era of putting out
video content, and if we move up a
little bit,
we then start to see the first video.
Hi.
If you're looking to improve your mood,
then stay with us.
I've got seven really simple steps
that you can follow.
They're all based on research evidence
and-
And now when we get to this point,
something I want you to think about
is how brave
you actually have to be in the onset of
creating content.
This is really intimidating,
especially someone with professional
credentials.
I'm sure that as a personal trainer,
I could get out and talk about anything.
But being a psychologist,
you've got to worry about peers,
qualifications, being
stripped of titles,
saying the wrong thing.
And to set up a camera
and just talk to camera,
making a little set here, it takes
courage. And you see Dr. Julie now,
and you might think she's just a natural.
You might think that she just
was born being good at creating content,
but she
won't mind me saying this,
she probably looks back
and cringes at this.
And actually,
I used to show people your old YouTube
videos, and Dr.
Julie, you unlisted them, you cheeky fox,
or someone in your team did.
I knew you wouldn't be unlisted Instagram
posts. I knew you'd be here.
So the point I want to make here
is there is a journey here that I
could only show people.
Here you got 2,000 views.
Now you're getting millions of views.
You started to add music.
Let me go up a little bit further.
Stop scrolling. Close-
Good hook. Stop scrolling
... this. Listen to my voice.
I want you to think of one thing
that you feel really thankful for
today.
3,900 views. She's trying things out,
different hooks, different
approaches, and the performance
is starting to increase with it.
So straight away, 11,000 views.
What's different? There
is now a visual hook.
I want to show you guys something I often
talk to my clients about in therapy.
If this is you and this
is all the layers of your life,
when something suddenly
triggers anxiety,
let's say you get asked to do a pres-
She would've gone, "Okay, hold on.
Using a visual prop in my content made it
outperform." Because if you look at the
views here on other stuff,
you'll notice that having something in her
hand
gave her nearly double the amount of
views.
So let me go up a little bit further.
Tried one in the car, didn't do that well.
Winter blues, didn't do that well.
Let's have a look. I'm sure there
is going to be an outlier.
And then here there's another type,
pointing at things,
and we all remember these
from TikTok. It was a trend, it was 2020.
Dr.
Julie is finding her feet. And look,
there are times here of
stagnation. Actually, that's likes,
not views. Ignore me there.
5,000, 1,000.
Let me come up a little bit further.
I do apologize for digging up these
skeletons, Dr. Julie. Cool. Okay.
Here we go. Her first big outlier.
I want to talk to you guys about
overthinking because I've seen a lot of
bad advice
about this on the internet.
Overthinking is not anything that's wrong
with you.
It's a normal part of being a human,
and we all do it, but we do more of it
when we're under-
And this point here, I guarantee,
and I'm not going to speak on your behalf
because
we've never met yet,
and I don't actually know you that well.
There's going to happen something where
you get this many views on a video.
You're going to think to yourself, "Oh,
this has got potential.
This could work."
And there's an emotion in you where you
go, "This could change my
life." Now,
before you have one of these moments,
it's very difficult for you to
actually believe me with what I'm saying
here.
Then once you think, "Okay,
300,000 people," that's like Twickenham
Stadium full to the brim,
nearly four times over of people
that watched your video.
And then you go back to normal.
You go back into the valley of despair
and you think, "Oh, this isn't working
again." And then you bring the same prop
out that worked for you before.
Let's do a confidence check-in. If this
is you and these are all the layers of
confidence you can build over time
The same prop can be reused. And then 14K,
11K,
11K, 10K, 15K. Everyone now is
pumping,
and you create a little bit of an aura to
you when you're doing
this as part of your content.
You start to think, "This is working."
And then
people start complimenting you.
Then someone would've said to you in
Waitrose, "Oh
my God, I love your content,"
and it makes you gassed to go home
and make more
content.
Here's five essentials for your anxiety
toolkit.
Number one is understanding
that you're not-
Improved your pacing
and your cadence speaking in content.
Here's three steps to taking something off
your mind.
Number-
You are so much more confident here,
and it's through repetition.
At this point,
you've been doing it about a year.
But I would go as far as to say there's no
book deal at this point.
Okay, then you get your first TV gig,
and it's because they would've seen you on
social media.
We can talk now to psychologist Dr.
Julie Smith,
who joins us from Hampshire this morning.
And-
And look, 20K, 17K, 34K, 30K,
67K.
I feel like I'm enjoying your come up with
you here.
Now we're going to scroll a little bit
further, I hope you don't mind.
But the crazy thing is,
there could've been a moment here where
you make this-
One of the fundamental tools for-
And you get 6,000 likes, which
is still quite a lot,
and people might just think
you're mad.
I bet your friends at some point,
even your husband, were like, "Why do
you keep making those bloody reels?"
And it literally is a journey of
years of decent views or whatever.
And then we start getting a lot closer to,
the only thing I can call it is mastery.
If you feel lost in life,
it doesn't matter how-
We've now swapped from an iPhone to a
professional camera.
There is professional audio here.
You work.
I would probably say maybe,
I don't think you're wearing a mic.
I actually think you've probably got some
kind of Sennheiser MKH
416 pointing down here.
I think we might have even moved into a
studio.
And how much you achieve.
If you're living your life based on
someone
else's values and not your own-
And then there's some at home,
some in the studio.
And then it looks like here we make the
move into a studio because ultimately the
trajectory that you're on,
you've had to make a decision.
Similar to right now, I'm in a studio.
It's got air conditioning, it's all mine,
it's soundproofed, it's everything.
Because there's a point you have to go
professional with this.
Here's four signs
that a friendship may be coming to an end.
Number one-
I'll forgive you.
Then we come up to the top,
and the views on these are going to
be massive. 15 million, 8 million,
7 million, 2.8 million.
And the thing is, Dr.
Julie here has accrued so much goodwill,
she can ask
for anything, and she'll get it.
She can say, "Buy my book,
come to my event,"
whatever it is. "Join my free newsletter,
'Ultimate Panic Attack Guide.'" Wow,
love that. Million copy bestselling book,
flex.
And also the title,
"Why Has No One Told Me This Before?"
is an absolute
unbelievable title of a book.
I'm very jealous about that,
I'm not going to lie.
The journey of mastering content creation
is a
lonely,
weird path where people think you're
mental.
You feel like you're going insane.
Even right now,
spending time talking to a camera, hoping
strangers on the internet will watch it
when it's been edited.
And I can't stress this enough.
I've been making content now for nine
years.
If you'd met me three years into making
videos, you would've thought that I was
fucking insane. I had no online clients.
I'd never made money from it.
I had maybe 3,000 or 4,000 followers.
But there was something just deep down
where I was like, if I can keep making
content that helps people,
it's going to pay me back in the future.
And again, a lot of you know Ed,
the YouTube sensei.
I put this in my Discord the other day.
If we go back to some of his earliest
videos.
Show you how to make a business vlog,
we thought we'd show you how we make our
own.
[laughs] Crap.
And then takes us on to editing. What?
We haven't even filmed yet.
The lesson here is
everyone eats shit in the beginning.
Everyone doesn't know
if it's going to work.
Everyone just has to put out content,
and it's only the people that can keep
going and post hundreds of posts that
are going to attain that level of
mastery necessary for success.
Imagine this is the amount of content
that you
need to do to get success in whatever it
is you want to do.
It's here that things start to work.
And it's just before it
that every single person gives up.
I want to personally thank Dr.
Julie for setting such a fantastic
example of what good content should
and could look like,
and you can imitate
that into any other realm.
You can be a personal trainer
and be like same setup, visual hook,
setup,
payoff, et cetera.
So I hope you've enjoyed
that little deep dive into
Dr. Julie's history, and hopefully
that can inspire you to
be the next Dr. Julie.
You don't even have to be a psychiatrist.
You could do it in any realm.
You could be a physio, be the next Dr.
Julie.
There are going to be links in the
description to all the ways you can work
with me
and access the stuff that I do. And
if you're interested in
watching more of my content,
there's a video here
that YouTube's recommended that I
think you'll really love.
Thanks for watching.